chris.com 2019-12-27

# Chris | Privacy Policy

Last update: 08/09/2019

 **Section 1: Information on the collection of personal data**

(1) We provide information in the following on the collection of personal data during the use of our website (chris.com). Personal data are all data that relate to you personally, such as your name, address, email addresses and user behavior.

(2) The controllers, as defined by Art. 4, para. 7 of the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), is Holger G. Weiss, German Auto Labs GAL GmbH, Köpenicker Strasse 154a, 10997 Berlin, Email: [mail@germanautolabs.com](mailto:mail@germanautolabs.com)(see our imprint). You can contact our data protection officer at [datenschutz@germanautolabs.com](mailto:datenschutz@germanautolabs.com) or via our postal address by including “Data Protection Officer” in the address.

(3) When you contact us by email, chat, telephone, or via a contact form, we will store the data you share with us (your email address and possibly your name and phone number) in order to respond to your questions as well as to be able to provide you with the best possible service in the future.

(4) In the event that we commission service providers for individual functions of our website or would like to use your data for commercial purposes, we will inform you of the relevant procedures in detail below. We will also specify the criteria that have been established for determining the storage period.

 **Section 2: Your rights**

(1) You have the following rights regarding our use of the personal data that relates to you:

–     The right to information

–     The right to rectification and deletion

–     The right to restriction of processing

–     The right to object to the processing

–     The right to data portability

(2) In addition, you have the right to file a complaint with a data protection supervisory authority concerning our processing of your personal data.

Berliner Beauftragte für Datenschutz und Informationsfreiheit [Berlin Data Protection and Freedom of Information Commissioners]

Address: Friedrichstr. 219, 10969 Berlin

Visitor entrance: Puttkamerstr. 16-18

Telephone: +49 30 13889-0

Email: mailbox@datenschutz-berlin.de

 **Section 3: Collection of personal data when visiting our website**

(1) When the website is used for purely informational purposes, i.e., when you do not register or otherwise share information with us, we only collect the personal data that your browser transmits to our server. If you wish to view our website, we must collect the following data that are technically required to display our website and to ensure its stability and security (legal basis: Art. 6, para. 1, no. 1 (f) of the GDPR):

–     IP address

–     Date and time of the request

–     Time zone difference with respect to Greenwich Mean Time (GMT)

–     Content of the request (specific page)

–     Access status/HTTP status codes

–     The volume of data transmitted in each case

–     Website from which the request is sent

–     Browser

–     Operating system and its interface

–     Language and version of the browser software

(2) In addition to the aforementioned data, cookies will be stored on your computer when you use our website. Cookies are small text files that are stored on your hard drive and allocated to the browser used by you and are used to forward certain information to the site that installed the cookie (in this case by us). Cookies cannot execute programs or transmit viruses to your computer. They are used to make the website more user-friendly and effective.

(3) Use of cookies:

a) This website uses the following types of cookies, the scope and function of which are explained below:

–     Transient cookies (see b)

–     Persistent cookies (see c)

b) Transient cookies are automatically deleted when you close your browser. These particularly include session cookies. Session cookies store what is called a session ID with which the various requests made by your browser are allocated to a collective session. This allows your computer to be recognized again when you return to our website. Session cookies are deleted when you log out or close your browser.

c) Persistent cookies are automatically deleted after a predetermined period of time that may vary between cookies. You can delete the cookies at any time in your browser’s security settings.

d) Your browser settings can be configured according to your wishes. For example, you can reject the acceptance of third-party cookies or all cookies. Please note that if you do this, you may not be able to use all of the functions of this website.

(4) Cookies from third-party providers

a)    In order to improve our website as well as for economic interests, such as reminding interested website visitors of our offers (remarketing), we use third-party cookies as described below:

  * WordPress (necessary for the website’s operation)
  * Woocommerce (ecommerce plugin)
  * Elementor (landing page plugin)
  * Cookie Consent (cookie consent plugin)
  * Google Analytics (anonymized web analysis to improve the website)
  * Google (A/B testing, remarketing)
  * Salesforce (customer support chat)
  * Facebook (remarketing, web analysis)
  * Google Doubleclick (remarketing, web analysis)
  * Youtube (remarketing)
  * Twitter (remarketing, web analysis)
  * PayPal (payments)
  * Stripe (payments)

b) When you visit our website, we notify you of our use of the described third-party cookies. An option for preventing these cookies from being stored on your computer can be found in your browser’s settings (legal basis: Art. 6, para. 1 (f) of the GDPR).

(5) In order to process your order, we work together with the following service provider(s), who support us in whole or in part in the execution of concluded contracts. Certain personal data will be transmitted to these service providers in accordance with the following information.

The personal data collected by us are passed on to the transport company commissioned with the delivery within the framework of contract processing, insofar as this is necessary for the delivery of the goods.

We pass on your payment data to the commissioned credit institution within the scope of payment processing, insofar as this is necessary for payment processing. If payment service providers are used, we will inform you explicitly below. Legal basis for the passing on of the data is Art. 6, para. 1, no. 1 (b) of the GDPR.

  * If you choose to pay via PayPal, we pass on your payment details to PayPal is processed by PayPal (Europe) S.à r.l. & Cie, S.C.A., 22-24 Boulevard Royal, L-2449 Luxembourg within the framework of the payment processing. The transfer takes place in accordance with Art. 6 Para. 1 lit. b DSGVO and only insofar as this is necessary for payment processing. You can find additional information about PayPal data protection in the [Data Protection Declaration of PayPal: https://www.paypal.com/de/webapps/mpp/ua/useragreement-full?locale.x=en_DE.](https://www.paypal.com/de/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full?locale.x=en_DE)

  * If you decide to pay by credit card, the payment will be processed by the payment service provider Stripe, Inc., 510 Townsend Street, San Francisco, CA 94103, USA, to whom we forward the information you provide during the ordering process together with the information about your order in accordance with Art. 6 Para. 1 lit. b DSGVO. Your data will be passed on exclusively for the purpose of processing payments with the payment service provider Stripe and only to the extent that it is necessary for this purpose. Stripe has certified to the EU-U.S. and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework. You can find additional information about Stripe data protection in the [Data Protection Declaration of Stripe](https://stripe.com/de/privacy): https://stripe.com/de/privacy

  * If you choose to pay via Klarna we pass on your payment details to Klarna Bank AB (publ) Sveavägen 46, 111 34 Stockholm, Sweden within the framework of the payment processing. The transfer takes place in accordance with Art. 6 Para. 1 lit. b DSGVO and only insofar as this is necessary for payment processing. You can find additional information about Klarna data protection in the [Data Protection Declaration of Klarna](http://cdn.klarna.com/1.0/shared/content/legal/terms/Klarna/en_gb/privacy?_ga=2.20239547.2036017274.1562684972-590924982.1562684972): http://cdn.klarna.com/1.0/shared/content/legal/terms/Klarna/en_gb/privacy?_ga=2.123781834.1185818526.1564742865-1145722870.1564742865

 **Section 4: Objecting or withdrawing consent to the processing of your data**

(1) If you have consented to the processing of your data, you may withdraw your consent at any time. Such a withdrawal of consent will affect the reliability of the processing of your data after you have sent us the declaration of your withdrawal.

(2) To the extent that we process your data on the basis of a balance of interests, you may object to the processing of your data. This is the case, if the processing is not specifically necessary for the fulfillment of a contract, which is indicated by us in each case in the following description of functions. When submitting such an objection, please explain the reasons why we should not process your personal data in the manner implemented by us. In the event of a justified objection, we will review the facts and either cease/adapt the processing of your data or demonstrate our compelling legitimate grounds, on the basis of which we will continue to process the data.

(3) Of course, you may object to the processing of your personal data for the purposes of advertising and data analysis at any time. You can notify us of your objection to advertising using the following contact information:via email: [datenschutz@germanautolabs.com](mailto:datenschutz@germanautolabs.com)or via our postal address by including “Advertising Objection” in the address: German Auto Labs GAL GmbH, Köpenicker Strasse 154a, 10997 Berlin.

 **Section 5: Newsletter**

(1) With your consent, you can subscribe to our newsletter, which we use to inform you of our current interesting offers. The advertised goods and services are specified in the declaration of consent.

(2) For the subscription to our newsletter, we use what is known as the double-opt-in procedure. This means that, after you subscribe, we will send an email to the email address provided asking you to confirm that you would like to receive the newsletter. If you do not confirm your subscription, then your information will be blocked and automatically deleted after one month. Moreover, we will store the times of the subscription and confirmation as well as the IP address you used in each case. The purpose of this procedure is to verify your subscription and to be able to detect a possible abuse of your personal data.

(3) Your email address is the only information required to send you the newsletter. Providing additional, separately marked data is voluntary; such data will be used to address you personally. After we receive your confirmation, we will store your email address for the purpose of sending the newsletter. Legal basis: Art. 6, para. 1, no. 1 (a) of the GDPR.

(4) You may withdraw your consent to receiving the newsletter and unsubscribe from the newsletter at any time. You can declare your withdrawal by clicking on the link provided in every newsletter email by sending an email to datenschutz@germanautolabs.com, or by sending a message via the contact information provided in the imprint.

(5) Please note that we evaluate your user behavior when you receive the newsletter. For this evaluation, the emails we send contain what are known as web beacons or tracking pixels, which are one-pixel image files that are stored on our website. In conducting evaluations, we combine the data mentioned in Section 3 and the web beacons with your email address and individual ID. We use the data obtained in this way to create a user profile so that we can tailor the newsletter to your individual interests. In doing so, we record when you read our newsletter and which links you click within the newsletter to draw conclusions about your personal interests. We combine these data with actions you take on our website.

You can object to this tracking at any time by clicking on the separate link provided in each email or by notifying us via another contact option. The information will be stored for as long as you subscribe to the newsletter. After you unsubscribe, we store the data anonymously and in a purely statistical form.

 **Section 6: Online Advertising**

1\. Amazon Associates Program

(1) German Auto Labs GAL GmbH participates in the Associates Program of Amazon Europe S. à. r. l. and is an affiliate of the advertising program that was designed to provide a medium by which referral fees can be earned by placing ads and links to amazon.de on a website. Our objective in participating in this program is to display ads that are of interest to you and to make our website more interesting for our users.

(2) In order to display advertisements, statistical information about you is collected and then processed by our advertising partners. When you visit our website, Amazon receives the information that you visited the corresponding page of our website. In addition, Amazon assesses your needs via web beacons and may also store a cookie on your computer. The data mentioned under Section 3 of this Policy are transmitted. We have no influence on the data that are collected, and the full scope of the data collection and the storage period are not known to us. When you are logged into Amazon, your data can be directly allocated to your Amazon account. If you do not want your data to be allocated to your Amazon profile, you must log out. Your data may possibly be transferred to Amazon’s contractual partners and to authorities. We have no influence on the data that are collected, and the full scope of the data collection is not known to us. The data are transferred to the USA and are evaluated there. Legal basis for the processing of your data: Art. 6, para. 1, no. 1 (f) of the GDPR.

(3) There are several ways in which you can prevent the cookies of the Amazon Associates Program from being installed: a) by changing the settings of your browser software; in particular, by rejecting third-party cookies, you will not receive ads from third-party providers; b) by deactivating the interest-related ads at Amazon via the link http://www.amazon.de/gp/dra/info; c) by deactivating the interest-related ads of providers who are part of the self-regulation campaign “About Ads” using the link http://www.aboutads.info/choices; these settings will be deleted when you delete your cookies. Please note that, if you do so, you may not be able to fully use all of the functions of this website.

(4) Aside from the above information included in this Privacy Policy, additional information regarding the purpose and scope of the data collection and processing as well as regarding your associated rights and the setting options to protect your privacy can be found at: Amazon EU S.à.r.l, Amazon Services Europe S.à.r.l., and Amazon Media EU S.à.r.l., all of which are registered at 5, Rue Plaetis, L–2338 Luxembourg; Email: ad-feedback@amazon.de.

Amazon is subject to the EU-US Privacy Shield, https://www.privacyshield.gov/EU-US-Framework. Additional information regarding the use of data by Amazon can be found in the enterprise’s Privacy Policy: http://www.amazon.de/gp/help/customer/display.html/ref=footer_privacy?ie=UTF8&nodeId=3312401 and at: <http://www.amazon.de/gp/BIT/InternetBasedAds>.

2\. Use of Google Adwords Conversion Tracking

(1) We use the service of Google Adwords to draw attention to our attractive offers with the help of advertising material (Google Adwords) on external websites. Using the data of such ad campaigns, we can assess how successful the individual advertising measures are. Our objective for this is to display ads that are of interest to you, to make our website more interesting for you, and to attain a fair calculation of advertising costs.

(2) This advertising material is delivered by Google via “ad servers.” In addition, we use ad server cookies, which allow us to measure certain parameters of success, such as the display of ads or clicks by users. If you reach our website via a Google ad, Google Adwords will store a cookie on your PC. These cookies generally expire after 30 days and are not intended to identify you personally. As a rule, the unique cookie ID, the number of ad impressions per ad (frequency), the last impression (relevant for post-view conversions), and opt-out information (indication that the user does not wish to be addressed again) are stored as analytical values for this cookie.

(3) These cookies allow Google to recognize your Internet browser. If a user visits certain pages of an Adwords client’s website and the cookie stored on the user’s computer has not yet expired, Google and the client can recognize that the user clicked on the ad and was forwarded to this page. Each Adwords client is assigned a different cookie. Cookies can therefore not be traced via the websites of Adwords clients. We do not collect and process any personal data using the above-mentioned advertising. Google merely provides us with statistical evaluations. Based on these evaluations, we can recognize which of our implemented advertising measures are particularly effective. We do not receive additional data from the use of advertising material; in particular, we cannot identify users based on this information.

(4) As a result of the marketing tools used, your browser automatically establishes a direct connection with the Google server. We have no influence on the scope and the further use of the data that are collected by Google as a result of using this tool and are therefore providing you with the information at our disposal: the use of AdWords conversion tracking means that Google receives the information that you have visited the corresponding section of our website or have clicked on one of our ads. If you are registered with a service provided by Google, Google can allocate your visit to your account. Even if you are not registered with Google or are not logged into your account, it is possible that the provider will recognize and store your IP address.

(5) There are several ways that can prevent your participation in this tracking process: a) by changing the settings of your browser software; in particular, by rejecting third-party cookies, you will not receive ads from third-party providers; b) by deactivating the cookies for conversion tracking by configuring your browser settings in such a way that cookies from the domain “www.googleadservices.com” are blocked, using https://www.google.de/settings/ads; these settings will be deleted when you delete your cookies; c) by deactivating the interest-related ads of providers who are part of the self-regulation campaign “About Ads” using the link http://www.aboutads.info/choices; these settings will be deleted when you delete your cookies; d) by means of a permanent deactivation in your Firefox, Internet Explorer, or Google Chrome browsers using the link http://www.google.com/settings/ads/plugin. Please note that if you do this, you may not be able to fully use all of the functions of this website.

(6) Legal basis for the processing of your data: Art. 6, para. 1, no. 1 (f) of the GDPR. Additional information regarding Google’s policies on data privacy can be found here: http://www.google.com/intl/de/policies/privacy and https://services.google.com/sitestats/de.html. Alternatively, you can visit the website of the Network Advertising Initiative (NAI) at http://www.networkadvertising.org. Google is subject to the EU-US Privacy Shield, <https://www.privacyshield.gov/EU-US-Framework>.

3\. Remarketing

In addition to Adwords conversion tracking, we use the Google remarketing service. Remarketing is a process we use to remind you of our offers. By using this application, our ads can be displayed to you during your use of the Internet after you have visited our website. This is done by means of cookies that are stored on your browser and that Google uses to record and evaluate your user behavior when visiting various websites. This allows Google to determine when you previously visited our website. According to Google’s own statements, Google does not combine the data collected in the context of remarketing with personal data that Google may have stored in relation to you. In particular, according to Google, data are pseudonymized during remarketing.

4\. DoubleClick by Google

(1) This website also uses the online marketing tool DoubleClick by Google. DoubleClick uses cookies to display ads that are relevant to the user, to improve reports on the campaign’s success, or to avoid repeatedly showing the same ad to a particular user. Google uses a cookie ID to record which ads are displayed in which browser and can thus prevent this ad from being displayed multiple times. Furthermore, with the help of cookie IDs, DoubleClick can record “conversions” that are related to requests concerning ads. This is the case, for instance, when a user sees a DoubleClick ad and later visits the advertiser’s website and makes a purchase there using the same browser. According to Google, DoubleClick cookies do not contain personal data.

(2) As a result of the marketing tools used, your browser automatically establishes a direct connection with the Google server. We have no influence on the scope and the further use of the data that are collected by Google as a result of using this tool and are therefore providing you with the information at our disposal: the use of DoubleClick means that Google receives the information that you have visited the corresponding section of our website or have clicked on one of our ads. If you are registered with a service provided by Google, then Google can allocate your visit to your account. Even if you are not registered with Google or are not logged into your account, it is possible that the provider will recognize and store your IP address.

(3) There are several ways to prevent your participation in this tracking process: a) by changing the settings of your browser software; in particular, by rejecting third-party cookies, you will not receive ads from third-party providers; b) by deactivating the cookies for conversion tracking by configuring your browser settings in such a way that cookies from the domain “www.googleadservices.com” are blocked, using https://www.google.de/settings/ads; these settings will be deleted when you delete your cookies; c) by deactivating the interest-related ads of providers who are part of the self-regulation campaign “About Ads” using the link http://www.aboutads.info/choices; these settings will be deleted when you delete your cookies; d) by means of a permanent deactivation in your Firefox, Internet Explorer, or Google Chrome browsers using the link http://www.google.com/settings/ads/plugin. Please note that if you do this, you may not be able to fully use all of the functions of this website.

(4) The legal basis for the processing of your data: Art. 6, para. 1, no. 1 (f) of the GDPR. Additional information regarding DoubleClick by Google can be found at https://www.google.de/doubleclick and http://support.google.com/adsense/answer/2839090; additional information regarding Google’s policies on data privacy, in general, can be found at https://www.google.de/intl/de/policies/privacy. Alternatively, you can visit the website of the Network Advertising Initiative (NAI) at http://www.networkadvertising.org. Google is subject to the EU-US Privacy Shield, https://www.privacyshield.gov/EU-US-Framework.

5\. Facebook Custom Audiences

(1) In addition, our website uses the “Custom Audiences” remarketing tool of Facebook Inc. (“Facebook”). With this tool, interest-related ads (“Facebook Ads”) can be displayed to users of the website when they visit the social network Facebook or other websites that also use this tool. Our objective in using this tool is to display ads that are of interest to you and to thereby make our website more interesting for you.

(2) As a result of the marketing tools used, your browser automatically establishes a direct connection with the Facebook server. We have no influence on the scope and the further use of the data that are collected by Facebook as a result of using this tool and are therefore providing you with the information at our disposal: the use of Facebook Custom Audiences means that Facebook receives the information that you have visited the corresponding page of our website or have clicked on one of our ads. If you are registered with a service provided by Facebook, Facebook can allocate your visit to your account. Even if you are not registered with Facebook or are not logged into your account, it is possible that the provider will recognize and store your IP address as well as other identifying factors.

(3) The “Facebook Custom Audiences” tool can be deactivated [here and] at [https://www.facebook.com/settings/?tab=ads#_](https://www.facebook.com/settings/?tab=ads#_m%C3%B6glich)if you are a registered user.

(4) Legal basis for the processing of your data: Art. 6, para. 1, no. 1 (f) of the GDPR. Additional information on data processing by Facebook can be found at https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy.

6\. A/B Testing

(1) This website also analyzes user behavior by means of A/B testing. This means that we may display our website with slightly varying content depending on the profile that has been assigned to a user. In this way, we can analyze and regularly improve our website and make it more interesting for you as a user. Legal basis for the A/B testing: Art. 6, para. 1, no. 1 (f) of the GDPR.

7\. Integration of YouTube Videos

(1) Our website integrates YouTube videos that are stored at http://www.YouTube.com and can be played directly on our website.

(2) When you visit our website, YouTube receives the information that you visited the corresponding subpage of our website. In addition, the data mentioned under Section 3 of this Policy are transmitted. This occurs regardless of whether you have logged into a user account provided by YouTube or do not have a user account. When you are logged into Google, your data will be directly allocated to your account. If you do not want your data to be allocated to your profile in YouTube, you must log out before clicking the button. YouTube stores your data as a user profile and uses them for the purposes of advertising, market research, and/or to adapt its website to your needs. Such an evaluation is conducted, in particular (and even for users who are not logged in), to display appropriate advertising and to inform other users of the social network of your activities on our website. You have the right to object to the creation of such user profiles; you must contact YouTube if you wish to exercise this right.

(3) Additional information regarding the purpose and scope of the data collection and processing by YouTube can be found in their Privacy Policy, which also includes additional information regarding your rights and setting options to protect your privacy: https://www.google.de/intl/de/policies/privacy. Google also processes your personal data in the USA and is subject to the EU-US Privacy Shield, <https://www.privacyshield.gov/EU-US-Framework>.
